(サスケ)守る… 守るだと？
Protect?
Did you say protect?!
なんの冗談だ…。
You've got to be kidding!
(マダラ)もう一度 言う。
I'll say it once more...
お前は 兄のことを
知っているようで何も知らない。
You think you know about your brother,
but you know nothing.
If you continue speaking
such nonsense, I'll kill you!
それ以上 ふざけたことを
ぬかせば お前を殺す。
どうやら ひと筋縄では
いかなそうだな。
You're not making this easy, are you?
まあ ムリもない。
I suppose that's natural though...
怪しげなヤツに
こんなことを急に言われてもな。
Suddenly being told such a story
by a stranger like me.
だが オレの話していることは事実。
But what I tell you is the truth.
イタチからも聞いただろう？
あの夜の協力者のことを。
Itachi did mention it, did he not?
About his accomplice that night.
オレが その うちはマダラだ。
I am that  Madara Uchiha.
イタチのことなら
なんでも知っている。
I know everything about Itachi.
まあ イタチは そのことに
気づかずに死んだがな。
I suppose Itachi died
without realizing that.
うるせぇ!! そんなことは
もう どうだっていい！
Shut up!
Such things don't matter anymore!
オレの前から消えろ！
Just get out of my sight!
いや 聞いてもらう。
お前は 聞かなくてはならない。
No, you will listen.
You need to hear this.
それが お前の義務だ。
It's your obligation!
忍の世のため
木ノ葉のため そして何より➡
For the sake of the ninja world...
For the sake of
the Hidden Leaf Village...
And for your sake...
弟のお前のために
すべてを懸けた兄➡
Your brother risked everything.
You will know how Itachi Uchiha lived!
うちはイタチの生きざまを。
わかるか？
Do you know why?
イタチが なぜ お前の眼に
天照を仕込んだか。
Why Itachi implanted Amaterasu
into your eye?
ハア… ハア… ハア…。
お前とオレを イタチは どうしても
引き合わせたくなかったからだ。
Itachi was determined to make sure
that you and I would not meet.
その理由は
オレの話を聞けば すべてわかる。
You will understand why,
as well as everything else,
when you hear me out.
イタチの真実を知る者は
木ノ葉のダンゾウと三代目 火影➡
Those who knew the truth about Itachi
were Danzo of the Hidden Leaf,
the Third Hokage,
そして 相談役の２人
ホムラとコハルの４人だけだった。
and his advisors Homura and Koharu.
Just those four.
三代目が死に 今
それを知るのは年寄りばかり３人。
The Third Hokage died...
and now, there are only three aging folk.
ヤツらは これから先も絶対に➡
Still, those three will probably
never reveal the abominable truth.
あの忌まわしい事実を
口外しないだろう。
イタチの真実は 永久に闇へと消える。
The truth about Itachi will fade
into darkness forever.
そして イタチも それを望んでいた。
And that is what Itachi wished.
だが オレも
イタチの真実を知っている。
However, I know the truth
about Itachi too.
さっきも言ったな。
As I said earlier...
Itachi died without realizing that.
イタチは そのことについては
気づかずに死んだと。
しかし 念には念… イタチは
オレを信用していなかったようだ。
However, he wanted to
make doubly sure.
It seems Itachi did not trust me.
万に一つ その真実を
知るやもしれぬと➡
So just in case I did know the truth,
天照で オレの口を閉ざそうとした。
he planned to silence me
with the Amaterasu.
お前と話をするために➡
He probably anticipated I would show
my Sharingan
オレが写輪眼を見せることまで
計算していたんだろう。
in order to speak to you.
何を言ってる…。
What is this?
何を言ってんだ？ コイツ…。
What is this guy saying?
オレを守る… 守る？ 真実… だと？
Protect me?
Protect?!
The truth?
思い出せ。
Think back.
イタチのことを
ゆっくりと思い出してみろ。
Think carefully and
remember about Itachi.
ハア… ハア… ハア…。
お前の優しかった兄を…。
About your kind brother.
((イタチ : どうした？
What's wrong?
This is it, right?
The place where Father works.
ここでしょ？
父さんが働いてるところ。
木ノ葉警務部隊の本部だ。
This is the headquarters of
the Hidden Leaf Police Force.
前から気になってたんだけど➡
I've always been curious.
何で 警務部隊のマークに
うちは一族の家紋が入ってるの？
Why is the Uchiha crest
on the police force logo?
なんだ 気づいてたのか？
当たり前だろ！
What? You noticed that?
Who wouldn't?
うん そうだな。
Well...let's see...
簡単に言うと
この警務部隊を組織し➡
Simply put, it seems our ancestors formed
and organized this police force.
設立したのが うちは一族の
先代たちだったらしい。
だからこの組織のシンボルマークに
自分たちの家紋をつけたのさ。
And so, they used our family crest
as the symbol of this organization.
昔からうちは一族は この里の
治安をずっと預かり守ってきた。
From ages past,
our clan has been entrusted
with the safety of the village.
うちはの家紋は その誇り高き
一族の証しでもあるんだよ。
The Uchiha crest reflects
the pride of our clan.
今や うちは一族も
小さくなってしまったけど➡
While its numbers have dwindled,
今でもほぼ全員が
ここの第一分隊に所属し➡
even today, nearly everyone in
the clan serves on Squad One
里の治安維持に貢献している。
and is dedicated to preserving
the peace and safety of the village.
忍の起こす犯罪を
取り締まれるのは➡
After all, only exceptional ninja are capable
of preventing crimes that ninja commit.
更に 優秀な忍だけだからな。
《やっぱり父さんはすごいや》
Father is great, after all!
兄さんもここに入るの？
Are you going to work here too?
さあ どうかな。
I wonder about that...
(そうしなよ))
You should!
No, he...
いや アイツは アイツは
オレを殺そうとしたじゃないか！
He tried to kill me!
オレの眼を奪おうと。
He tried to take my eyes...
Who would do such a thing?!
((誰がこんなことを！
愚かなる弟よ。
Foolish little brother...
(万華鏡写輪眼！))
Mangekyo Sharingan!
落ち着け。
Calm down!
ゆっくり息をしろ。
Breathe slowly.
Don't touch me!
オレに触るな！
((例え 憎まれようともな。
Even if you do hate me...
(それが兄貴ってもんだ))
That's what big brothers are for.
((許せ サスケ。 また今度だ))
Sorry, Sasuke... Another time.
Fate
気がついたか？
You're awake...
悪いが 拘束させてもらった。
Sorry, but I took the liberty
of tying you up.
おとなしく 話を聞いて
もらえそうもなかったからな。
Since you weren't gonna stay still
and listen to me.
アイツは… イタチは敵だ。
He... Itachi was my enemy.
父さんと母さんを殺し
一族を皆殺しに…。
He killed our parents...
He killed everyone in the clan.
抜け忍で… 暁のメンバーだ。
He was a Rogue Ninja...
A member of the Akatsuki...
アイツは憎むべき存在だ。
He was despicable.
オレの目的…。
He was my target.
あの夜… ヤツが うちは一族を
皆殺しにしたのは 事実だ。
It's true...
that he annihilated
the Uchiha clan that night.
そして 木ノ葉を抜けた。
And he deserted the Hidden Leaf.
だったら…。
Then...
そして そうすることが
木ノ葉から下された任務だった。
And that is what he was ordered
to do by the Hidden Leaf.
それが イタチの真実への入り口だ。
That is the beginning of
the truth about Itachi.
任務だと!?
It was his mission?
そうだ。 あの夜 イタチは己を殺し
任務をやり遂げたのだ。
Yes.
That night,
Itachi killed his personal feelings
and fulfilled his mission.
少し 落ち着いたようだな。
It seems you've calmed down a bit.
どういうことだ？
What are you talking about?!
イタチの話をするには➡
In order to talk about Itachi,
木ノ葉創立の時代まで
話をさかのぼらねばならない。
I must take you back to the early days
when Hidden Leaf Village was founded.
イタチは犠牲になったのだ。
Itachi sacrificed himself.
古くから続く因縁…
その犠牲にな。
This is fate that has continued
since ages past.
He was sacrificed for it.
犠牲？
そうだ。
Sacrifice?
That's correct.
そもそもが 木ノ葉隠れの里が
生まれたときからある➡
A huge problem rooted since the time
Hidden Leaf Village was founded.
大きな問題だ。
それが イタチの生き様を決めた。
That is what determined Itachi's life.
少し 長い話になるが➡
It's a long story,
but everything I tell you is the truth.
これから話すことは
すべて事実だ。
何を根拠に信じろと？
お前は信用できない。
On what basis should I believe you?
You're untrustworthy.
提示できる証拠はない。
There's nothing I can show you
as proof.
オレの話を信じるかどうかは
お前が決めればいい。
And it's up to you whether
you believe me or not.
だが 話は 最後まで聞いてもらう。
But you will hear me out until I finish.
いいだろう。 話せ。
Fine... So talk.
フッ…。
今より 80年以上も前の話だ。
It all started more
than 80 years ago.
(マダラ)かつて 世界は
戦いの絶えない 戦国時代だった。
The world was in turmoil.
It was the age of war.
国々は 自国の利権や➡
Nations battled for power and
to increase their territories.
領土拡大のために
争いを続けていた。
その戦乱の時代… 忍の組織は
一族単位の武装集団でしかなく➡
During this age of war,
ninjas consisted of individual clans
serving as armed units.
それぞれの一族は国に雇われ
戦争に参加していた。
They were hired by various nations
to participate in the fighting.
そして その数多くの
忍一族の中にあって➡
And among the many ninja clans,
two were feared as the strongest.
最強と恐れられた
二つの一族があった。
それが 我らが うちは一族と➡
One was us, the Uchiha clan.
森の千手一族と呼ばれる
一族だった。
And the other was known
as the Forest's Senju Clan.
我ら うちは一族は
頭抜けたチャクラと写輪眼を有し➡
We of the Uchiha clan possessed
exceptional chakra and the Sharingan.
あらゆる戦闘に長けた
いわゆる 戦闘一族として➡
Excelling in all types of warfare,
we became known as a battle clan.
知れ渡っていた。
そして オレは
その うちは一族の中でも➡
And I was born into the Uchiha clan,
特別に強いチャクラを持つ者として
生まれた。
possessing chakra that
was especially powerful.
しぶとく生き長らえているのが
その証といってもいい。
Perhaps the fact that I've lived
this long is proof of that.
かつてのオレは
戦いに明け暮れていた。
Back in those days,
all I did was battle.
力が ものをいう時代。
In an age defined by power,
オレは より強い力を求め
友も弟も この手にかけた。
I sought to become ever stronger
and killed my friends and
even my younger brother.
キサマ…。
Why you...!
だが そのおかげで
完全なる万華鏡を手に入れ➡
As a result, I came into possession
of the perfect Mangekyo Sharingan,
オレは うちはのリーダーとなった。
and became the leader of the Uchiha.
そして その力を使い
幾度となく 千手一族と戦った。
And using that power,
I fought the Senju clan countless times.
千手一族の長…
柱間を相手にするには➡
It was inevitable that I face Hashirama,
the leader of the Senju clan.
仕方のないことだったのだ。
後に 初代火影となる
木遁の千手柱間…。
"Wood Style" Hashirama Senju,
the future first Hokage.
この忍の世界の頂点であり
オレのあこがれの忍だった。
The one who stood at
the top of the ninja world...
And the one I respected most.
(マダラ)火影の名を初めて名乗った男
柱間が率いる千手一族は➡
The Senju clan, led by Hashirama
who became the First Hokage,
どの忍一族からも一目置かれ
何より恐れられていた。
was feared and respected
by all the other clans.
千手が動けば うちはが動く。
If the Senju moved,
so did the Uchiha.
ヤツらを相手にできるのは
我が一族ぐらいのものだった。
Our clan was probably the only clan
able to compete with them.
千手を雇えば
対立国は うちはを雇う。
If a nation hired the Senju,
the opposing nation would hire
the Uchiha.
まるで ライバルだ。
We were like rivals.
柱間と対立するうち オレの名も
どんどんと知られていった。
The more I went up against Hashirama,
the more my name became known
as well.
((イタチ : 高みに近づくため
その器を量るためだ))
To get close to the top...
to measure my abilities...
名を上げる…。
To heighten your reputation...
そんなことのために
弟の眼を奪ったのか？
You took your younger brother's eyes
just for that?!
奪った… だが それは
うちは一族を守るための力が➡
I did take them.
But I needed power in order
to protect the Uchiha.
必要だったからだ。
守るためだと？
Protect?
そう うちはの名が上がれば
おのずと敵も増える。
Yes. As the Uchiha name spread,
its enemies increased.
激しい争いの中で➡
It was a necessary sacrifice
to protect the clan
千手一族をはじめとする
外敵から一族を守るには➡
during the fierce fighting with the Senju,
and the other clans.
必要な犠牲だった。
名を上げるためではない。
It was not for my fame.
弟は すべて承知のうえだった。
My younger brother was
in total agreement
自ら眼を差し出したのだ。
and offered his eyes to me.
だが あるとき
千手一族は うちはに対して➡
But one day,
the Senju clan offered a truce.
休戦を申し出てきた。
うちはは これに同意した。
And the Uchiha accepted it.
双方の一族の誰もが➡
Everyone, in both clans,
had grown weary of the fighting
長く終わりのない戦いに
疲れ切っていた。
that had dragged on for so long.
限界にきていたのだ。
They had enough.
だが オレは
休戦に ただ一人 反対した。
But I...
I was the only one who opposed it.
今までの憎しみは
どこに行ったというのだ？
Where has all the hate gone?!
弟は 何のために
犠牲になったというのだ!?
For what purpose had my brother
sacrificed himself?!
しょせん
うちはと千手は水と油だ。
The Uchiha and Senju are
like oil and water.
いずれ うちは一族は
千手一族によって➡
I couldn't help fearing that in time,
the Uchiha clan would come to
be oppressed by the Senju clan.
駆逐されてしまう
そう思えてならなかった。
だが うちは一族の皆は
休戦を望んでやまなかった。
However...everyone in the Uchiha clan
wanted a truce.
オレはリーダーとして しかたなく
皆の意志を汲み取った。
As their leader, I had no choice
but to go along with their wishes.
それから ほどなく➡
Shortly thereafter, the ninja alliance
signed a pact with the Land of Fire,
我ら忍連合は
領土の平定を望んでいた➡
火の国との協定に こぎつける。
which had sought dominion
over the territories.
そこに一国一里の
強固な組織ができあがった。
The secure one nation, one village system
was formed
and became the Land of Fire and
the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
火の国と木ノ葉隠れの里だ。
一国一里のシステムを
あらゆる国々が真似ていった。
Other countries adopted
the one nation, one village system.
それにともない
争いも徐々に鎮火していく。
And subsequently,
the fires of war were extinguished.
ひとたびの平和だ。
Momentary peace.
だが 木ノ葉は
ある出来事によって➡
But due to a certain incident,
すぐ混乱に陥った。
the Hidden Leaf Village quickly
descended into turmoil.
ある出来事？
A certain incident?
里長 初代火影の座をめぐる
争いだ。
A fight...for the First Hokage's seat.
お前も知るとおり
その座を得たのは 千手柱間だ。
As you know, the first to occupy
that seat was Hashirama Senju.
火の国も里の皆も柱間を選んだ。
The Land of Fire and
the entire clan chose Hashirama.
うちはが主権の座から
どんどんと遠ざかっていくのは➡
It was inevitable
that the Uchiha's hold on
the reins of power would loosen.
明らかだった。
オレは うちはを守るため➡
I decided that the Uchiha
should take leadership...
うちは主導の道を
選ぶことを決めた。
柱間と対峙する道をいくことを…。
That we should confront Hashirama...
しかし うちはの者でさえ➡
But no one, not even from
the Uchiha clan, supported me.
オレに ついてくる者は
いなかった。
部下たちは 再び争いの火種を➡
My subordinates, who did not wish
to light the fires of war,
起こそうとする
オレをうとましく思い➡
were unsympathetic and betrayed me.
裏切ったのだ。
オレは 利己的な欲求に
突き動かされていると叩かれ➡
I was accused of acting
out of greed and self-interest.
それどころか
己の命を守るために➡
Not only that...
They scorned me as
a selfish brother
弟の眼を奪った
欲深い兄だと さげすまれた。
who stole his younger brother's eyes
in order to save his own.
どこに好き好んで
弟を傷つける兄がいる…。
What brother would willfully
hurt his younger brother?!
オレは ただ… うちはを
守りたかっただけだというのに。
I just...I just wanted to
protect the Uchiha!
オレは 里を出た。
すべてに裏切られてな。
I left the village.
Everyone betrayed me.
そして 復讐者となり
木ノ葉隠れの里に戦いを挑んだ。
I became an avenger and declared
war on the Hidden Leaf Village.
(マダラ)だが オレは敗れた。
And I lost...
終末の谷と呼ばれるようになった
あの場所でな。
At that place which became known
as the Final Valley.
I was said...to have died there.
オレはあそこで死んだとされている。
柱間でさえ そう思ったはずだ。
Even Hashirama believed it.
オレは 皆から そして 歴史から
忘れ去られていった。
And everyone forgot about me...
History forgot about me.
柱間の弟である 二代目火影は➡
Hashirama's younger brother
who became the Second Hokage
二度と
オレのような反逆者を出さぬため➡
was determined that there would
never be a traitor like me again.
So, as proof of his trust, he granted
the Uchiha a special position...
信頼の証しとして
うちはに 特別な役職を与えた。
木ノ葉警務部隊の設立だ。
And he created
the Hidden Leaf Police Force.
しかし その実際は
里の政から うちはを遠ざけ➡
But the truth is...
This was to further distance the Uchiha
from the reins of government.
Furthermore, it was a way to keep
a close eye on the entire clan.
なおかつ 一族を ひとまとめに
監視下に置くためのものだった。
その意図に気づく
うちはの者もいた。
There were Uchiha members
who realized this...
Members who wanted to carry
on my rebellion.
オレの意志を継ぐ
造反勢力も出てきた。
が… 時 すでに遅し。
But...it was too late.
時は流れ 主権は千手の手に。
Time passed...
The Senju clan solidified
its hold on power
誇り高き うちは一族は
千手の犬へと成り下がった。
and the Uchiha fell to
becoming Senju dogs.
そして
オレの考えたとおりになった。
And what I predicted came to pass.
ある事件で うちはは
完全に駆逐されてしまう。
A certain other incident sealed
Uchiha's figurative demise.
そう…
16年前の 九尾の妖狐 襲来だ。
Yes...
The attack of the Nine-Tailed Fox Demon
16 years ago.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
九尾を手なずけ コントロールすることが
できるのは うちはの瞳力だけだ。
The Nine-Tails can only be tamed
and controlled
by the ocular powers of the Uchiha.
木ノ葉の上役たちは あの事件を➡
The higher-ups of Hidden Leaf Village
perceived the Uchiha
うちはの何者かによる
しわざではないかと勘ぐった。
to be behind this attack.
あれは 自然発生的な
いわば 天災だ。
That was a natural occurrence,
a natural calamity.
The Uchiha had nothing to do with it.
うちはは関係していない。
だが あらぬ疑いがかけられた。
Yet suspicion fell on them...
うちはが主権を狙って 反逆を
起こそうとしたのではないか と。
That the Uchiha had revolted
and sought to take power.
以降 うちはへの監視は
暗部によって徹底され➡
As a result,
the Uchiha was put under
the strict surveillance of
the Anbu Black Ops,
and they were forced to relocate
to the outskirts of the village.
一族の居住地は
里の片隅へと追いやられ➡
隔離さながらの状態になった。
唯一 三代目火影だけは
その処置に異議を唱えたが➡
暗部のダンゾウ そして 相談役たちは
それを認めなかった。
しょせん うちは一族は
信用されていなかったのだ。
差別が始まった。
ヤツらの不信は わだかまりを生み
疑いはやがて 現実となっていく。
うちは一族は クーデターを企んだ。
里を乗っ取るために…。
そして 木ノ葉上層部は➡
うちは一族の中に
スパイを送り込んだ。
それが お前の兄 うちはイタチだ。
そこから
イタチの地獄は始まったのだ。
＜791年 ハルジオン港。
ナツたちが天狼島で
消息を絶ってから➡
すでに ７年の歳月が流れていた＞
(ビスカ)いつまで海を見てるんだい。
(アルザック)
仕事も終わったし ギルドに戻ろう。